<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--Edit status: not edited-->
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="NSXv_overview">
  <title><ph conkeyref="HOS-conrefs/product-title"/>Integrating with NSX for vSphere</title>
  <abstract><shortdesc outputclass="hdphidden">Overview of the integration process for VMWare's
      NSX-v Neutron-server plugin.</shortdesc></abstract>
  <body>
    <!--not tested-->
    <section id="NSXv_about">
      <p>VMware's NSX embeds networking and security functionality, normally handled by hardware,
        directly into the hypervisor. </p>
      <p>NSX can reproduce, in software, an entire networking environment, and provides a complete
        set of logical networking elements and services including logical switching, routing,
        firewalling, load balancing, VPN, QoS, and monitoring. Virtual networks are programmatically
        provisioned and managed independent of the underlying hardware.</p>
      <p>VMware's Neutron-server plugin called NSX for vSphere (NSX-v) has been tested by the
          <keyword keyref="kw-hos"/> team under the following scenarios:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Virtual <keyword keyref="kw-hos"/> deployment</li>
        <li>Baremetal <keyword keyref="kw-hos"/> deployment</li>
      </ul>
      <p>We provide installation instructions for both scenarios, however deploying on virtual
        machines is supported only through Professional Services at this time as it is a non-core
        feature. For more details on core vs non-core features, see <xref
          href="../../liberty_features.dita"/>. </p>
      <note type="important">This documentation is only meant as an example of how to integrate
        VMware's NSX-v Neutron plugin with <keyword keyref="kw-hos"/>. The examples in this
        documentation may not be suitable for all environments. To configure this for your specific
        environment, use the following design guide created by VMware, which you can view on
        VMware's website at <xref
          href="https://communities.vmware.com/servlet/JiveServlet/downloadBody/27683-102-8-41631/NSX"
          scope="external" format="html">Reference Design: VMware® NSX for vSphere (NSX) Network
          Virtualization Design Guide</xref>.</note>
    </section>
  </body>
</topic>
