<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "concept.dtd" >
<topic xml:lang="en-us" id="knownissues30">
    <title>Known Issues in this Release</title>
    <body>

        <section>
            <title>Fact cache entry isn't valid</title>
            <p><!--https://jira.hpcloud.net/browse/HLM-3357--> If at the very start of an Ansible
                run you see a message like the following:
                <codeblock>
Fact cache entry for host COMPUTE-0002 isn't valid, deleting and failing
Fact cache entry for host COMPUTE-0001 isn't valid, deleting and failing
ERROR: The JSON cache files COMPUTE-0002, COMPUTE-0001 were corrupt, or did not otherwise contain valid JSON data. They have been removed, so you can re-run your command now.
</codeblock>
                Then please just re-run your Ansible command. </p>
        </section>


        <section>
            <title>Compute (Nova)</title>
            <p><!-- DOCS-2653 --> The <codeph>policy.json</codeph> file for the Nova service has
                been changed, although the location of the file remains the same:</p>
            <p>Old name/location: <codeph>~/helion/my_cloud/config/nova/policy.json</codeph></p>
            <p>New name/location: <codeph>~/helion/my_cloud/config/nova/policy.json.j2</codeph></p>
            <p>If you have made changes to this file in your environment, you should recreate these
                changes in the new file.</p>
            <p><b>Live Migration between KVM and RHEL Compute Hosts Isn't Supported</b></p>
            <p>If you are using both Linux for HPE Helion (KVM) and RHEL compute hosts, you cannot
                live migrate instances between them. Instances on KVM hosts can only be live
                migrated to other KVM hosts and the same for RHEL hosts. For more details about live
                migration, see <xref href="operations/live_migration.dita"/>.</p>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Block Storage (Cinder)</title>
            <p><!-- DOCS-2878 --> Although <keyword keyref="kw-hos-version-30"/> supports encrypted
                Block Storage volumes, the following limitations apply: <ul>
                    <li>Creating encrypted volumes from an image is not supported.</li>
                    <li>Creating encrypted volumes when using a Ceph backend is not supported. This
                        bug can be seen <xref href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/nova/+bug/1463525"
                            scope="external" format="html">here</xref>.</li>
                </ul></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Identity (Keystone)</title>
            <p><!-- DOCS-2513 --> There will be performance degradation to a user's account in your
                cloud environment if the number of roles assigned to that user goes above ~1000. You
                are advised to use the user account functionality in an efficient way so that this
                does not become an issue. This was reported in upstream OpenStack <xref
                    href="https://bugs.launchpad.net/keystone/+bug/1499555" scope="external"
                    format="html">here</xref>.</p>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Bare Metal (Ironic)</title>
            <p>Multipath in not supported for the boot device. In case multiple paths exist use
                zoning so that only one path is available. </p>
            <p> If there are multiple NICs that are connected to the Management network, and the
                first NIC does not have access, then deployment will fail. Ensure that the first
                NIC’s connection is UP. </p>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Network (Neutron)</title>
            <!-- DOCS-2857 -->
            <p>VM's may not get an IP address from the DHCP server when creating VMs in large scale.
                This may occur when booting a large number of VMs at the same time when all of the
                networking may not be up in time before the DHCP retries timeout. If this occurs,
                reboot the VM.</p>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>VPNaaS (Neutron)</title>
            <!--DOCS-2840-->
            <p>In <keyword keyref="kw-hos"/> 2.X and <keyword keyref="kw-hos-phrase-30"/> the
                Metering agent cannot be used in conjunction with VPNaaS.</p>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>Octavia (Neutron)</title>
            <!--DOCS-2879-->
            <p>Octavia on <keyword keyref="kw-hos-phrase-30"/> requires KVM based compute nodes but
                also supports mixed environments. Octavia on <keyword keyref="kw-hos-phrase-30"/> is
                not suitable for highly available or high throughput production environments and in
                these cases HPE’s Helion certified 3rd party hardware load balancer should be
                used.</p>
        </section>
    </body>
</topic>
