<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="A10_verify">
  <title>Verify A10 Integration</title>
  <body>

    <p>To verify A10 Networks LBaaS integration with Helion OpenStack, you will create two subnets, one externally-accessible public network, and one internal private network. The networks should be connected with a Neutron router. The test instances and loadbalancer VIP will be created on the private subnet, and the VIP will be accessed from the public network using floating IP.</p>
     <p>To very integration, complete all items in the following checklist:</p>
    <table frame="all" rowsep="1" colsep="1" id="table_ckx_A10_vfy">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="25pt"/>
        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1*"/>
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry>&#9744;</entry>
            <entry>Item</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry/>
            <entry>Create networks and subnets
            <ol>
              <li>Create public networks</li>
              <li>Create private networks</li>
              <li>Create a router connecting these networks</li>
            </ol>
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry/>
            <entry>Boot at least 2 instances on a private subnet running a simple web server
            <ol>
              <li>Define appropriate security groups allowing ICMP, SSH, and HTTP traffic</li>
              <li>Configure each web server so that its output easily identifies which instance it is running on</li>
              <li>Use the <codeph>curl</codeph> command to verify that the web servers can transfer data between them</li>
            </ol>
            </entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry/>
            <entry>Create a Pool</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry/>
            <entry>Create a VIP on the private subnet</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry/>
            <entry>Create Members for each web server instance</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry/>
            <entry>Create a floating IP on the public network and associate it with the VIP</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry/>
            <entry>Log into the A10 device dashboard and observe that appropriate objects have been created on the device</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry/>
            <entry>Boot an instance on the public networka. Log into this instance and:
              <ol>
                <li>Use <codeph>curl</codeph> to query the floating IP associated with the VIP</li>
                <li>Configure each web server so that the output easily identifies which instance it is running on</li>
                <li>Repeated queries of the VIP FIP should show load balancing between the members</li>
              </ol>
            </entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
    
  </body>
</topic>
